THOMAS ARCHBOLD

32 Purbrook Estate, Tower Bridge Road, London, SE1 3BZ tomjarchbold@gmail.com \diamond +44 7837 674 419 \diamond tomarchbold.com

BACKGROUND

I am a second-year Ph.D. student at King's College London where I am part of the Distributed Artificial Intelligence group. My research interests are in algorithmic game theory and mechanism design, as well as other areas of theoretical computer science including algorithms and complexity theory.

EDUCATION

MPhil/Ph.D. Computer Science, King's College London

2020-2024 (expected)

Research interests: algorithmic game theory and mechanism design, theoretical computer science

Supervisor: Professor Carmine Ventre

MSc. Computer Science, University of Warwick

2019-2020

Classification: Distinction

Dissertation title: A Decentralised Peer-Prediction Market (awarded distinction)

BSc. (Hons) Computer Science, University of Warwick

2016-2019

Classification: 2-1

Dissertation title: An Educational Kernel for the Raspberry Pi (awarded first class)

EXPERIENCE

Graduate Teaching Assistant, King's College London

Jan 2021-present

- 6CCS3OME Optimization Methods

2020/21

Private Tutor Oct 2020-present

Tutor privately for maths and computer science, from GCSE up to undergraduate level. Requires planning and delivering engaging lessons and providing effective feedback.

Software Graphics Engineer Intern, Imagination Technologies, Kings Langley

Jul 2019-Sep 2019

Worked with the PowerVR Vulkan driver team researching Google's ANGLE API to analyse its performance on the driver, and wrote OpenGLES and Vulkan programs to test specific areas of its functionality. Contributed driver code and discussed progress and plans in weekly team meetings.

INVOLVEMENT

Seminar Organiser, Distributed Artificial Intelligence group, King's College London

Jan 2021-present

Help to organise the fortnightly seminar within the Distributed Artificial Intelligence research group, which involves contacting internal and external speakers to present talks on their work and chairing the meetings.

Conference Volunteer

- International Colloquium on Automata, Languages, and Programming (ICALP)

Jul 2021

Sub-reviewer

- Algorithmic Decision Theory (ADT)

Jun 2021

Poster presenter, International Conference for Undergraduate Research 2018

Sep 2018

Presented individual research project on "Cellular Automata and Computational Universality" at the ICUR. Produced an introductory primer on cellular automata and their applications plus visualisation software.

LANGUAGES AND SKILLS

Programming Languages

C, C++, Python, Lisp, Java, Bash

Tools Languages Pandas, Numpy, Sklearn, Keras, GDB, Valgrind, Git, LATEX

French (B2/upper intermediate)

Russian (B1/intermediate)

WIDER ACTIVITIES AND ACHIEVEMENTS

First XV Player of the Season, University of Warwick RFC

2019/20, 2018/19

UWRFC First XV, QE Boys Rugby First XV, QE Boys Cricket First XI

2016-20, 2014-16, 2015-16